《诉讼双雄》前情提要
艾弗里·麦肯诺曾经是
Avery McKernon was the first client
我带进律所的第一位客户
I ever brought into the firm.
我拿我的引擎和布伦森
I have stacked my engines up against Bronson
以及世界所有的引擎比过
and everyone else's in the world,
我的引擎完胜
and mine win,
因为我确保它们是全世界设计得最好的
Because I make sure they're designed better than anyone else's.
那这就是你的演讲内容
And that's the speech you're gonna give.
我说过要把麦肯诺的一半业务给你
I said I was giving you 50% of Mckernon.
但没说我会保留另一半
I didn't say I was keeping the other 50%.
你终于意识到他们的代理需要升级了
You finally realized they need an upgrade in representation?
都取决于你  杰克
It's up to you, Jack.
要么支持C35条款
Stand by provision C35
要么就滚蛋
or pack up your shit.
我想让你告诉我
I want you to tell me
你作为心理医生犯的最严重的一次错误是什么
the worst mistake you ever made as a therapist?
我们之前可没约定这个
That wasn't part of the deal.
-我害死了一个人  -什么
- I killed someone. - What?
一个客户需要人把他儿子从戒毒所弄出来
A client needed someone to get his son out of rehab
好让他去参加他妈妈的葬礼
so that he could attend his mother's funeral.
我内心深处知道他还没准备好
I knew deep down inside he wasn't ready,
但依然给他放行了
but I gave the go-ahead anyway,
就在葬礼当晚...
and the night of the funeral...
他吸毒过量致死
he overdosed and died.
我很意外你又预约来了
I'm surprised you called for another appointment.
还能说什么呢
What can I say?
你给我讲的那个故事打动了我
You telling me that story got to me.
所以你准备好说实话了吗
So you're ready to tell the truth?
准备好了  出现在我梦中的女人是唐娜
I am. The woman in my dream was Donna.
但我觉得你梦中的女人其实并不是唐娜
I don't think the woman in your dream was actually Donna.
我觉得是你母亲
I think it was your mother.
真是难以相信
I don't believe it.
我把困扰了我好几天的事情告诉了你
I tell you the thing that's been eating at me for days,
你却说我撒谎吗
and you call me a liar?
不  我不是说你撒谎
No, I'm not calling you a liar.
你的梦是一系列未决问题的结合重演
Your dream was a representation of unresolved issues.
唯一的未决问题是我向你吐露心声
The only unresolved issue is I told you the truth,
你却来攻击我
and you're turning on me.
提你母亲不是攻击你
Bringing up your mother isn't turning on you.
你完全不了解提我母亲对我意味着什么
You have no idea what bringing up my mother is to me.
我不了解
No, I don't.
但那正是我们现在所做一切的意义
That's the whole point of what we're doing here.
我们现在做什么都不重要了
Well, it doesn't matter what we're doing here,
因为我们结束了
'cause I'm not staying.
哈维  我不在乎你挣多少钱
Harvey, I don't care how much money you make
睡过多少女人
or how many women you sleep with.
你生命中有一些问题
You have issues in your life
会导致你难以获得真正的爱情
that are going to keep you from having real relationships.
你尽可以跟自己说
Now, you can tell yourself
这一切与你的母亲毫无干系
it has nothing to do with your mother all you want,
但那是自欺欺人  你自己也清楚
but it's a lie, and you know it.
我说过我们结束了
And I said we're done.
路易  我们得谈谈
Louis, we need to talk.
如果是关于那个有狐臭的暑假实习生
Oh, if it's about the summer associate with B.O.,
我无能为力
that is out of my control.
是关于杰克·索罗夫
It's about Jack Soloff.
什么  我发誓假如那混蛋
What? So help me, if that asshole
不守信用  我...
is backing out of his agreement, I--
没有人不守信用
No one's backing out of anything.
那是怎么回事
Well, then what's the problem?
目前什么事也没有
Right now there is no problem.
我们打败他了  他不反对我们了
We beat him. He's been neutralized.
但我可不希望他一直"不反对"
But that's not where I want him to stay.
什么意思
What do you mean?
意思是我们虽然赢了
I mean we've won,
但他证明了自己的能耐
but the man's shown himself to be a force.
假如他以后还要站在我们这边
And if he's ever gonna come around to being on our side,
我们得给他时间舔舐伤口
we have to give him time to lick his wounds.
我不管你怎么说
I don't care what you say,
但那只黄鼠狼绝不会跟我们一边的
but that weasel is never gonna be on our side.
就是你这种小心眼
And that's exactly the kind of petty thinking
让你和斯科特  哈德曼
that led to your feuds with Scottie, Hardman,
哈维  我  等人之间起了嫌隙
Harvey, me, just to name a few.
杰西卡  这不一样  你明白的
Jessica, this is different, and you know it.
杰克挑起了这整件事
Jack started this whole thing.
路易  昨晚你问
Louis, last night you asked
什么时候你才能学会听我的话
when were you going to learn to listen to me.
现在就开始吧
The time is now.
-但你说...  -我不管我说了什么
- And you said-- - I don't care what I said.
假如你在对待杰克的这件事上
If you let your pettiness
继续这么小心眼
get the better of you with Jack,
我敢断言
so help me god,
最后赢的绝对不是你
you will not be the one left standing.
我保证照你说的办
You have my word.
路易  我得和你谈谈
Louis, I need to talk to you,
但希望你别生气
and I don't want you to be upset.
怎么了
What is it?
多米尼克·巴伦刚刚打电话过来
Dominic Barone called.
他想过来开个会
He wants to come in for a meeting.
我知道他选择了打给我...
Now, I know he called me--
太好了  定个时间
Excellent. Pick a time.
你没因为他打给我而不是打给你而生气
But you're not mad that he called me instead of you?
我为什么要生气
Why would I be mad?
我没进错办公室吧
Am I in the right office?
迈克  那是原来的路易
Mike, you're thinking of the old Louis.
现在的路易可不是小心眼
The new Louis is not petty,
他也绝对不会因为谁打给谁
and he definitely does not get upset
这种事情而生气
about things like who called who.
我能问问这个新路易是从哪儿冒出来的吗
And may I ask where the new Louis came from?
从内心深处
From inside.
我对着镜子审视自己
I took a look at the man in the mirror,
并下定决心是时候做出改变了
and I decided it was time to make a change.
很开心你这样做
Well, I'm glad you did.
我不知道多米尼克有什么要求
And I don't know what Dominic wants,
但不管怎样
but whatever it is,
我期待就此事和你合作
I'm looking forward to working with you on it.
-你刚刚听见了吗  -听见了
- Did you just hear that? - Yes.
那你也明白一旦迈克和多米尼克约好了时间
Then you know once Mike and Dominic agree to a time,
你必须把它改期
you need to reschedule it.
路易
Louis.
多米尼克必须知道是我说了算
Dominic needs to learn that I'm the man in charge.
但事实并不是你说了算
But you're not the man in charge,
因为哈维让你和迈克共同代理麦肯诺汽车公司
because Harvey gave you and Mike McKernon Motors to share.
但多米尼克不知道这点
But Dominic doesn't know that,
迈克和我同时递给他名片
and Mike and I gave him a card at the same time.
迈克上面写着"助理律师"
And Mike's says "Associate,"
我的上面写着"皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特"
and mine says "Pearson Specter Litt,"
并且我像往常一样把"皮尔逊-斯佩克特"划掉了
and I crossed out the "Pearson Specter" like I always do.
路易  你没有听到杰西卡说的
Louis, did you not hear what Jessica said
不要那么小心眼吗
about stopping all the pettiness?
但那是说杰克·索罗夫的事
Yeah, that was about Jack Soloff.
不对  那说的是小心眼的事
No, it was about pettiness.
唐娜  对不起
Donna, I'm sorry, but I only have
但我不小心眼的额度有限
a certain amount of non-pettiness in me,
■
本字幕首发于字幕组网站
www.ZiMuZu.tv 欢迎交流
真正的路易·利特总要有发挥的地方
and the real Louis Litt needs to come out somewhere.
好吧  路易  如果你想让多米尼克认为是你说了算
Okay, louis, you want Dominic to think you're the man?
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
那你就不要纠结他电话打给了谁
Then you need to stop worrying about who he called
关心一下他的需求吧
and start worrying about what he needs,
也就是你要做个优秀的律师
which is for you to be a great lawyer.
很好  你在这
Good, you're here.
皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特
约翰逊的简报写好了吗
Did you file the Johnson brief?
-还没  -那今早弄好
- Not yet. - Then do it this morning.
我准备今天下午抓紧对付他们
I want to drop the hammer on those guys this afternoon.
在那之前  有个山姆·塔尔要见你
Well, before you do, there's a Sam Tull waiting to see you.
山姆·塔尔又是谁
Who the hell is Sam Tull?
条顺  盘靓  深邃的蓝眼睛
Tall, handsome, steely blue eyes?
没想起来
Not ringing any bells.
那也许这能让你想起来
Well, maybe this will knock the cobwebs out.
他说上次你见到他时
He said the last time you saw him,
他与莫雷洛资产管理公司共事
he was with Morello Asset management
你还威胁要修理他
and you threatened to kick his ass.
你让他进我办公室了
You let him in my office?
你觉得我有那么年幼无知吗
Do I look like I was born yesterday?
他现在在会议室
He's in the conference room
瑞秋·赞恩在看着他
under the supervision of one Rachel Zane.
我跟他说如果他不乖
I told him if he didn't behave himself,
我会亲自修理他
I'd kick his ass myself.
你一定会吧
You'd do that, wouldn't you?
我当然会
I sure as hell would.
如果你不马上过去
And if you don't get in there this second,
我也会修理你
I'll kick yours.
别跟我说你来
Don't tell me you're here
是为了接受我的挑战出去单挑的
to take me up on that offer to step outside.
我不是
I'm not.
那就好  那看来我们有共识
Good, then we've established
你比上次见面时聪明了
that you're smarter than the last time I saw you.
赶紧滚出我们的办公室
Now get the hell out of our offices.
哈维  人家专程来找我们的
Harvey, the man came to see us.
瑞秋  这人是个混蛋
Rachel, this man is an asshole,
他愿意让一个无辜的人承受牢狱之灾
and he was willing to let an innocent person go to jail.
我现在就是个有可能进监狱的无辜之人
And now I'm an innocent person who could go to jail.
什么
What?
我被指控进行未授权交易
I'm being accused of making unauthorized trades.
-被莫雷洛吗  -我不在那里工作了
- By Morello? - I don't work there anymore.
我现在在巴特勒
I work at Butler trading.
真不错  那他们到底授权没有
Good for you. Were they authorized or not?
我发誓我没有做任何
I swear to god I didn't do one thing
他们不知道的事
they don't know about.
让我猜猜  但你没证据
And let me guess, you don't have any proof?
对  没有
No, I don't...
因为事情就是这样运作的
Because that's the way things work.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
他的意思是他们检查过他的交易
It means he's saying they checked his trades
认可了风险
enough to decide it was okay with the risk
但是觉得不能落在纸面上
but not enough to put it in writing.
好吧  但他们为什么不把它落在纸面上
Okay, but why wouldn't they put it in writing?
因为他们宁愿说我欺诈
Because they would rather say I went rogue
也不愿缴纳两百万美元的罚款
than pay a $2 million fine.
但我的问题是  山姆
Here's the problem, Sam.
我为什么要相信你  上次我们见面时
Why should I believe you, when the last time we met
宁愿让一个无辜的人进监狱的可是你
you were the one who was willing to put an innocent person away?
因为我不知道她是无辜的
Because I didn't know she was innocent.
事实是...我完全不在乎
And the truth is... I didn't care.
但你在乎
But you did.
我实话跟你说
I'm telling you...
我没有做那些事
I didn't do this.
拜托  我需要你的帮助
Please, I need your help.
如果我发现你骗了我
If I find out you're lying to me,
这次可不只是威胁那么简单了
this time I won't just threaten you.
我绝对会弄死你
I will beat the shit out of you.
翻译： 潇湘月影 香茗小焙 Reginamoon 鱼小姐  木浅薰
翻译：王大可 杨一勾 某羽 小饭  CS漫画家小明
时间轴：风吹来的那片云     校对：木浅薰   潇湘月影
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第五季   第六集
唐娜  我能和你聊聊吗
Donna, could I talk to you for a minute?
可以  但你要告诉我蜂蜜被藏到哪里去了
Yeah, if you can tell me where the honey is hiding.
你这个狡猾的小熊
Oh, sneaky little bear.
你想说什么
So what's on your mind?
是这样  我在为婚礼
Okay, so I'm trying to plan
策划一些特别的创意
something special for our wedding.
什么  我们要结婚了吗
What? We're getting married?
迈克  这太突然了  我得想一想
Mike, this is so sudden. I'm gonna have to think about it.
那瑞秋怎么办  算了  谁管她
And what about Rachel? Oh, who cares about rachel?
-我爱你  -你演完了吗
- I love you. - Are you finished?
-必须吗  -唐娜  我很认真的
- Do I have to be? - Donna, I'm serious.
好吧  你需要什么
Okay, what do you need?
瑞秋告诉过我
Rachel told me it was her fantasy
她的梦想是生日那天在纽约广场酒店结婚
to get married on her birthday at the Plaza Hotel.
所以我打电话去订位  但是谁知...
So I called to arrange it, but then--
他们五年内都订满了
They're booked for the next five years.
你怎么知道
How did you know that?
你来找我不就因为这个吗  我无所不知
Same reason you came to me for help--I know what I know.
我需要跟那一样好的地方
Well, I need someplace just as good.
没有跟那一样好的地方
There is no place just as good.
那我该怎么办
So what am I supposed to do?
你已经做了你该做的
You already did what you're supposed to do.
向我求助
You came to me.
现在  把布罗迪放回去  这次别藏起来了
Now, put Brody back and don't hide him this time.
你给熊起了名字
You named the bear?
你还想要我帮忙吗
You want me to help you or not?
保罗·吉尔罗伊
Paul Gilroy.
我是  您是
Yes. And you are?
我是帮山姆·塔尔免除牢狱之灾的人
I'm the guy who's gonna keep Sam Tull out of jail.
如何免除呢  这位...
And how are you gonna do that, Mister--
斯佩克特
Specter.
哈维·斯佩克特
Harvey Specter.
你要交罚款  承认你的所作所为
You're gonna pay that fine and admit what you did.
抱歉我得让你失望了  斯佩克特先生
Well, I'm sorry to disappoint you, Mr. Specter,
但没做过的事  我是不会承认的
but there's no way I'm admitting to something I didn't do.
不管你承认不承认
Whether you admit it or not,
你都得写张支票
you're gonna write a check either way.
两百万还是三千万  由你决定
It's up to you whether it's for $2 million or $30 million.
我的同事似乎迟到了
My associate seems to be running late,
所以说吧  继续胡说八道吧
so go ahead, take me for a walk down bullshit lane.
我们告你  要求赔偿三千万
We're suing you for $30 million.
那我肯定还炒掉了其他五个人
Well, I must have fired five other people,
因为不当解雇的罚款上限是五百万
because wrongful termination's capped at $5 million.
我们不告你们不当解雇
We're not suing you for wrongful termination.
要告你们恶意指控
We're suing you for malicious prosecution.
你们不能这么做  我不是检察官
You can't do that. I'm not a prosecutor.
你不是  但你以莫须有的罪名
No, you're not, but you're framing my client
诬陷我的委托人
for a crime he didn't commit.
所以你自己决定  保罗
So it's up to you, Paul.
开张小支票  还是大的
Write the little check or the big check.
看你的了
Ball's in your court.
多米尼克  你来得很早啊  你好吗
Dominic, you're here early. How are you?
很好
Good.
其实  我在想上次来的时候
In fact, I was just thinking about the last time I was here.
你帮我当上了首席执行官
You were helping me become C.E.O..
得了  你是凭自己的力量当上首席执行官的
Oh, come on, you pretty much became C.E.O. all on your own.
我怎么当上的不重要
Well, it doesn't matter how I got there.
你得帮我保住这个位置
You're gonna help me stay there.
那是什么
What's that?
电池供电引擎的未来
The future of battery-powered engines.
我们很需要它  否则就会被淘汰
We need it, or we don't survive.
我猜这里有个问题
I'm guessing there's a catch.
问题就是  它很贵
The catch is it costs a fortune.
但我已经跟山脉科技首席执行官达成口头协议了
But I have a handshake deal with the C.E.O. of Range Tech.
我们是一起从技师起家的
We started as mechanics together,
如果我能两周内完成交易
and if I can close in two weeks,
他就把整个公司以我出得起的价钱卖给我
He'll sell me the whole company at a price I can afford.
如果我不能  他就面向市场出售
If I can't, he puts it on the market.
那我们不出十年就得关门
We'll be out of business in ten years.
这是怎么回事
What's going on?
我没来你们就开始谈了
You guys starting the meeting without me?
不  多米尼克到得早
No, Dominic just got here early,
但主题是
but the headline is
他希望我们两周内完成口头协议
he wants us to close a handshake deal
买下山脉科技
to buy Range Tech within the next two weeks,
我刚想告诉他我们可以帮他
And I was about to tell him that we could.
抱歉  但我们帮不了
Well, I'm sorry, but we can't.
为什么这么说
What do you mean you can't?
因为我们没法在两周内完成这样的交易
I mean there's no way that we can close a deal like this
除非跳过尽职调查这一步
in two weeks without skipping due diligence.
不  路易
No, Louis,
他和那个首席执行官是三十年的老交情了
he's known the C.E.O. for 30 years.
我们当然不能跳过这一步
So we don't have to skip it,
但我们可以来个精简版
but we can do a streamlined version.
好吧  或者我们完全不插手
Okay, well, then we might as well not do it at all.
如果规定时间内搞不定
We don't get it done in that time,
这个协议就不作数了
I can lose this deal.
他们设置了时限
They put a clock on it.
他们为什么这么做
And why would they do that?
我来告诉你为什么
I'll tell you why,
因为他们知道你不会留意
because they know you won't pay attention
他们想要蒙混过去的事
to whatever it is that they're trying to slide by you.
蒙混过去
Slide something by me?
他是我的朋友  我们有口头协议
This is my friend. We have a handshake deal.
口头协议算个屁
A handshake deal doesn't mean shit.
-路易  -没事的  迈克
- Louis! - It's okay, Mike.
显然路易不明白我的意思
Obviously Louis doesn't get me.
因为对我来说  口头协议意味着一切
Because to me, a handshake deal means everything.
所以下周请尽力做尽职调查什么的
So you do whatever due diligence you can in the next week,
因为如果你搞砸了我的交易
because if you mess up my deal,
我就去别的律所了
I'll be looking for a new law firm.
保罗·吉尔罗伊的律师来电话了
Paul Gilroy's lawyer called.
好快
That was fast.
想听坏消息还是更坏的消息
Want the bad news or the worse news?
为什么不都告诉我
Why don't you give me both
由我来决定到底算什么消息
and let me decide what kind of news it is.
他们不但拒绝交罚款
Not only are they not paying the fine.
还起草了驳回我们诉讼的动议
They also filed a motion to have our suit dismissed.
-我本该知道的  -本该知道什么
- Man, I should've known. - Should've known what?
你说你不介意多米尼克给我打电话找我开会
That you were full of shit when you said Dominic calling me
根本就是胡说
to set up that meeting didn't bother you.
我不管他打给谁
I don't care who he called.
我之所以那么干是因为客户至上
I did what I did in there because the client comes first.
胡说  你先对我然后对多米尼克敌意满满
Bullshit, you antagonized me and then Dominic.
咱俩参加的不是同一个会吗
Oh, what meeting were you in?
我没有对他有敌意  我是在保护他
I wasn't antagonizing him. I was protecting him.
是吗
Oh, really?
把他的主意说得一文不值还激怒他就叫保护吗
By shitting all over his idea and then pissing him off?
我不在乎我们是不是激怒了他
I don't care if we pissed him off.
他不需要朋友
He doesn't need a friend.
他需要的是我们做好我们的律师工作
What he needs is for us to be great lawyers.
路易  你可是有过因为别人不尊重你的级别
Louis, you have a history of getting bent out of shape
而大发雷霆的黑历史  所以别跟我扯
over hierarchy, so don't tell me
这事和你的所作所为没关系
that has nothing to do with this.
好吧  迈克  你说得对
Okay, fine, Mike. You know what, you're right.
我当时确实很生气  仅仅是当时
I did get bent out of shape. Did.
但随后我立刻就克制住了  因为就像我说的
But then I got over it, because as I said,
客户至上
the client comes first.
你真指望我相信这话吗
You really expect me to believe that?
迈克  几年前  多米尼克90%的时间
Mike, a few years ago, Dominic spent 90% of his time
都在研究引擎
under the hood.
他之所以急于实现这件事
He is rushing into this
是因为他觉得这是他唯一的机会  你知道的
because he feels it's his only chance, and you know it.
你觉得哈维会不做尽职调查就同意这件事吗
You think Harvey would sign off on this without due diligence?
让我猜猜  你希望我来做所有的工作吗
And let me guess, you expect me to do all the work?
不  你做一半  我做一半
No, you take half, I take half.
我们齐心协力
We do the work together.
你没听清我说的话
Oh, you're not hearing me.
-我当然听清了  -不  你没听清
- Oh, I'm hearing you. - No, you're not.
我是代表迈克尔·乔丹打这个电话的
I'm calling on behalf of Michael Jordan.
我不管你是代表谁打的
I don't care who you're calling for.
我们那天已经被订出去了
We're booked on that date.
可你的助手金妮说  史密斯夫妇
Oh, but your assistant, Ginny, said that the Smiths
可能想要...
might be willing to, um--
首先  她叫帕特丽夏  不叫金妮
First of all, it's Patricia, not Ginny.
其次  是麦克米伦夫妇  不是史密斯夫妇
And it's the Mcmillans, not the Smiths.
所以如果你没有别的事...
So, if you don't have anything else, then--
要知道  我问你的事情是合情合理的
You know what? That was a legitimate question,
你要是不那么粗鲁就好了
and it would be nice if you weren't so rude.
所以你最好至少发本宣传册来
So the least you can do is messenger over a brochure,
因为如果你不发
because if you don't,
乔丹先生就会打电话给广场酒店经理
Mr. Jordan is gonna call the manager of the Plaza
让你丢了饭碗
and get your ass fired.
路易  我需要和你谈谈
Louis, I need to talk to you.
我正要去找你呢
I was just on my way to see you.
关于那起正在进行的环保署调查吗
About the pending EPA investigation?
-真见鬼  -我还以为你在得意呢
- Shit. - I thought you'd be gloating.
你不正希望这样吗
You're the one who wanted this.
我不是希望这样  我是担心这样
I didn't want this. I feared this.
如果多米尼克买下山脉科技
If Dominic buys Range Tech,
就会惹上大麻烦
he's in huge trouble.
而如果我们告诉他这件事还没有解决方案
And if we tell him that without having a solution,
他就会炒了我们
he'll fire us.
我就是要说这个  我有解决方案
That's the thing. I have a solution.
我找到一家公司  他们有蓄电池部门
I found a company that has a battery division
我们可以买下来
that we can buy.
我们只要去找他们然后...
Now, we just have to approach them and--
不行  你没听到我说的话吗
No. Did you not just hear what I said?
我们不能危及他的交易
We cannot jeopardize his deal.
如果我们能让他们签保密协议
We won't be jeopardizing it
就不会危及到他的交易
if we can get them to sign a nondisclosure agreement.
我们让他们那样做的前提是
And the only way we'll be able to get them to do that
他们是我们的客户
is if they're our client.
所以幸好他们确实是我们的客户
Well, then it's a good thing they are.
你在我们自己客户里找了一家
You found one of our own clients?
你真是个天才
You're a genius.
但有一个小问题
Yeah, there's only one problem.
他们是杰克·索罗夫的客户
They're Jack Soloff's client.
那别想了  我们得另找一家公司
Forget it, we need to find another company.
没有别的公司了
There is no other company.
迈克  索罗夫绝不可能
Mike, there is no way that Soloff
和我们合作的  他恨透我了
will work with us on this. He hates me.
那我们就得想个办法让他不再恨你
Then we have to find a way to make him un-hate you,
我告诉你  这笔交易对杰克和我们
because I'm telling you, this deal is good for Jack,
都有好处
and it is good for us.
肯定会有办法的
There has to be a way.
那你去和他谈
Well, then you talk to him.
你是说你想让我
Are you--are you saying you want me
一个人去和索罗夫谈判吗
to negotiate with Soloff on my own?
我是说我们是一个团队  而索罗夫
I'm saying we're a team, and there's a better chance
对你点头的概率比对我要大得多
of soloff saying yes to you than to me.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
来领一份保密协议  你在这里干什么
I was just getting an NDA. What are you doing here?
我正在帮你呢
I am actually here for you.
我正在复印广场酒店的宣传册
I'm making copies of a brochure from the Plaza Hotel.
你搞定了吗
Wait, so you got it done?
没有  我给他们打电话
No, I called them,
他们表现得非常混蛋
and they were dicks,
反倒冲我发了一通火
And they got pissed at me.
所以你失败了吗
So you failed?
好吧
Okay.
如果你认为
If by "failed,"
我弄到了婚礼策划师
you mean I got the name
她的助手  和要举行婚礼那对夫妇的名字
of the wedding planner, her assistant,
还弄到了一本
the couple getting married,
印有他们抬头的宣传册  也算失败的话
and a brochure with their letterhead on it,
那么是的  迈克  我失败了
then, yeah, Mike, yeah, I failed.
唐娜  你确定你处理得了吧
Whoa, Donna, are you sure you can handle this?
你会跑去问一个大厨
Do you ask a chef who's cooking
他做的饭会不会好吃吗
if the meal's gonna turn out okay?
不会  你只管乖乖坐在那里
No, you sit back, you behave yourself
等着品尝你吃过的最美味的
until you get the best duck à l'orange
法式橙汁鸭胸
you've ever tasted.
我其实并不喜欢带橙汁的鸭肉
Yeah, I don't really like duck with orange stuff.
-出去  -我出去了
- Get out. - Gone.
我喜欢你做事的方式
I like the way you operate.
抱歉你说什么
Excuse me?
永远不让他们看到你担心冒汗
Never let them see you sweat.
你为什么觉得我在冒汗
What makes you think I'm sweating?
我看出来了
My eyes.
你或许能用那比喻哄骗那位小菜鸟
You may have fooled opie with that metaphor,
可你我都明白你现在连狗屁鸡胸都没有
but we both know you got duck à la shit.
新来的丫头  我不知道你以为你在和谁说话
Okay, new girl, I don't know who you think you're talking to,
可姐就是干这个的
but this is what I do.
你就是干这个的
What you do.
我干这行的时候
I've been doing shit like this
你还没出生呢
since you was an itch in your daddy's pants.
等等  你是在引用《致命凶器》[电影]吗
Hang on, did you just quote Lethal Weapon to me?
你听出来啦
You got that?
看来你还是有点智商的
Maybe you do have something.
下厨愉快  红发小美女
Good luck with your duck, red.
塔尔先生  你在巴特勒交易所工作多久了
Mr. Tull, how long have you been working at butler trading?
将近三年了
Almost three years.
那么在此期间
And how much money have you made
你为他们的客户赚到了多少钱
for their clients over that time?
大约一亿五千万美金
Approximately $150 million.
我直说了吧
So let me get this straight.
你交易  赔钱  他们并未干涉
You made a trade, lost money, they did nothing.
但当他们发现要为此支付罚金时
But the day they find out that they have to pay a fine,
又站出来说你没有得到许可
they said you were acting alone
并打算为此送你进监狱
and they're letting you go to jail?
没错
Exactly.
你怎么知道他们许可了你的交易呢
And how do you know they signed off on your trade?
因为大家都知道他们许可每一单交易
Because everyone knows that they sign off on every trade.
那么最终  谁该为
And, ultimately, who would be responsible
结束一个违反规定的交易负责呢
for stopping a trade that violated regulations?
保罗·吉尔罗伊
Paul Gilroy.
所以不可能是你明知道自己在犯错
So it couldn't possibly be that you knew what you were doing,
还是隐瞒下来  而其实一切都是你的错吗
you kept it secret, and that all of this is your fault?
可能  但事实并非如此
It could be, but it isn't.
真有意思
Well, that's interesting,
因为有人可以证明确实如此
Because we have somebody who says it is.
谁能证明
And who the hell is that?
-塔尔先生的心理医生  -什么
- Mr. Tull's therapist. - What?
心理医生不能透露和患者的对话
A therapist can't testify against their own patient.
如果付钱的是我们  他也签了弃权书就可以
She can if we paid for it and he signed a waiver,
他也签了
Which he did.
保拉·阿加德
塔尔先生  你的心理医生将提供证词
Mr. Tull, your therapist's testimony is coming,
到那时  你连交易资格都会丧失
and when it does, your ability to cut a deal goes away.
现在撤诉
Drop this matter,
没人会知道你看过心理医生
and no one ever knows you saw a therapist at all.
你去看公司提供的心理医生
You went to see a company-provided therapist,
为什么不告诉我
and you never told me?
我不知道这有关系
I didn't think it mattered.
关系大了去了
Well, it goddamn does.
你有告诉她是你干的吗
Did you tell this woman you did this?
没有  因为不是我干的
No, because I didn't do this.
但他们肯定不会是为此让她作证的
Well, they're not bringing her in to testify to that.
我跟她说我觉得愧疚
I told her that I felt guilty,
好像是我的错一样
as if the whole thing was my fault.
但我没说过是
I never said it was.
还不如说了呢
Well, you might as well have,
因为你这话谁听都会觉得就是你的错
because that's what it's gonna sound like.
-哈维  -你怎么能这么蠢
- Harvey-- - How could you be so stupid
居然向个陌生人敞开心扉
to confide your feelings to a stranger?
因为我需要帮助
Because I needed help.
如果你不讲出自己的真实感觉
And if you're not gonna talk about your feelings,
那还不如不去看心理医生呢
you might as well not see a therapist at all.
你最好希望监狱里也有心理医生
You better hope there are therapists in prison,
因为如果我不能阻止她作证
because if I can't stop her from testifying,
那监狱就是你的归宿
that's where you're gonna end up.
迈克·罗斯  什么风把你吹来了
Mike Ross, what brings you down to my office?
我是来代路易向你提议的
I'm here with a proposal from Louis.
你来是因为路易需要我的帮忙
You're here because Louis wants something from me,
但他自己不敢开口
but he's too afraid to ask.
他不是不敢
He's not afraid.
他让我来只是因为他觉得
He just sent me here because he figured
让我跟你谈会更好
you might hear it better coming from me.
麦肯诺汽车公司想在
Mckernon Motors wants to make an investment
电池技术方面做投资
in battery technology.
我们想和田中协商一下
We'd like to quietly negotiate with Tanaka,
需要你帮助我们说服他签这个
and we need your help getting them to sign this.
我为什么要那么做
And why would I do that?
因为投资是一大笔钱
Because it's huge money,
而且现在律所又有了提成奖励
and now that contingent compensation is back at the firm,
那对你也是一大笔钱
it's huge money for you.
上次路易给我的这种提议
And the last time Louis came to me with an offer like this,
完全就是个骗局
it was bullshit.
我不是路易  这也不是骗局
Well, I'm not Louis, and this isn't bullshit.
那我只有一个问题了
Then I guess I just have one question.
你能给我多少分成
How much of the deal are you authorized to give away?
五成  这已经够高了
50%, and that's more than fair.
也许是高  但我要全部
Maybe it is, but I want all of it.
你知道这对你的委托人也有好处  对吧
You know this helps your client, right?
我不在乎  要么全部要么免谈
I don't give a shit. All of it or none of it.
那就免谈
It's gonna be none of it,
而且你这完全是在往外扔钱
and you're just taking money out of your own pocket.
我不在意  因为这与钱无关
I don't care, because this isn't about money.
这是私仇  你走吧
It's about getting even, so run along.
告诉路易除非全部酬金都给我
Go tell Louis I'm not lifting a finger to help him
否则我决不帮他
unless I get everything.
你还真是个混蛋
Wow, you really are a dick.
我想这说明你听懂我的意思了
I take it that means you know where I stand.
杰西卡  你好  有什么能为你效劳的
Jessica, hi. What can I do for you?
婚礼筹划的如何了
How's the wedding planning going?
我们还在找婚礼办场
Oh, well, we're still looking for a venue,
但一切都很顺利
but things are moving along.
我听说这个阶段情侣经常吵架呢
I hear a lot of couples fight during this time.
我刚好有个够聪明的未婚夫
Well, I happen to have a fiance who's smart enough
让我全权负责了
to leave everything to me.
但你来不是为了这个
But that is not why you're here.
我想知道哈维情况如何
I want to know how Harvey's doing.
你是说案子的情况吗
With our case?
不  我问的就是他的情况
No, I just want to know how he's doing.
他很好
He's doing fine.
替我看着他
Keep an eye on him.
我会的
I will.
你来做什么
What are you doing here?
你明天要来我办公室
You're coming to my offices tomorrow
指证我的客户  你却不告诉我
to testify against my client and you didn't tell me?
我没告诉你是因为
I didn't tell you because this is the first
这是我头一次听说这事
I'm hearing about it.
胡扯  我都看到了
Bullshit, I saw it.
你收到了传票  要指证山姆·塔尔
You got subpoenaed to testify against Sam Tull.
在你冲进来之前
And until you just burst in here,
我根本不知道他是你的委托人
I had no idea he was your client.
无所谓了  因为你不能去
Well, it doesn't matter because you're not showing up.
那他们要逮捕我你也拦得住是吗
And you're going to stop them from arresting me, are you?
因为如果不去  我就会被逮捕
Because that's what will happen if I don't.
那就找个我这样的律师帮你解决这事
Then get yourself someone like me and get out of it.
那我告诉你
For your information,
我咨询过三个律师了
I have been to three different men like you,
因为我在乎山姆
because I care about Sam,
而且你比我更清楚
and you know better than I do
他一旦签了弃权书  我就别无选择
that once he signed that release, I have no choice.
我有办法给你选择
Well, I have a way to get you out of it,
你必须这么做
and you're gonna do it.
他们要是问你一些可能害他进监狱的问题
They ask you something that's gonna send him to jail,
你就说谎
you lie.
我不能这么做
I can't do that.
你能  你也会  他们不会知道的
You can, and you will, and they'll never know.
可我知道
I'll know.
就算我骗人骗己  还有记录呢
And even if I didn't, I have notes,
要是被他们发现  我就会进监狱
and if they found those, I'd be going to jail.
那就销毁记录  因为他是无辜的
Then destroy them, because he's innocent,
而且他那么信任你
and he trusted you with everything.
如果这对你不重要
And if that doesn't mean something to you,
那别人凭什么还要信任你
then why the hell should anyone ever trust you with anything?
哈维  这事和我们的事无关
Harvey, this isn't about us.
没人能逼我这么对你
No one can ever make me do that to you.
我想山姆·塔尔也是这么想的
I'm sure Sam Tull thought the same thing.
怎么样
Well?
没用的
It's not gonna work.
他拒绝了
He said no?
他说他要全部提成
He said he wants 100% of the deal.
-鬼扯  -我知道
- Piece of shit. - I know.
所以
So...
不知道  得另想他法了
I don't know. We're gonna have to think of something else.
给他吧
Give it to him.
-什么  -我说给他
- What? - I said give it to him.
路易  我知道多米尼克的案子
Louis, hey, I know we're under the gun
让我们压力很大  但我真的不觉得
with this Dominic thing, but I really don't think
放任他这样耍你是个好主意
it's a good idea to let him push you around like that.
我没放任他耍我
I'm not letting him push me around.
我是在听从指引
I'm listening to my leader.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
还记得吗  你问我新路易来自哪里
Remember when you asked me where the new Louis was coming from
我说是从自我中诞生的
and I told you from me?
其实不是
It wasn't from me.
是杰西卡
It was from Jessica.
她让我别再小气
She asked me to stop the pettiness once and for all.
如果我现在做不到  以后也永远做不到
And if I can't do that now, I'll never be able to do it.
好吧  看来我们只需要
Okay, then I guess all we have to do
想办法说服田中了
is figure out a way to sell the idea to Tanaka.
相信我
Oh, trust me.
这我都能做到  那个就是小菜一碟了
If I can do this, I definitely can do that.
路易  你干了什么啊
Louis, what the hell have you done?
怎么了  我在准备与田中的会面
What? I'm setting up for our meeting with Tanaka.
你逗我吗
Are you kidding me?
这又不是《打工好汉》
This isn't Gung Ho.
路易  他们看到你这样
Louis, they're gonna take one look at you,
肯定会被吓跑的
they're gonna run out the door.
不会的
No, they're not.
迈克  田中是个看重传统的日本公司
Mike, Tanaka's a Japanese company steeped in tradition.
我不管你怎么看待他们
I don't care what you think they are.
这太无礼了
This is offensive.
尊重他国文化
There's absolutely nothing offensive
绝对不是一种冒犯
about showing respect for another culture.
你又懂什么日本文化呢
And what do you know about their culture?
迈克  相信我
Mike, trust me.
我上初中的时候
When I was in junior high,
学校有个交换生
we had an exchange student stay with us.
优琪
Ooh, Suki.
又来了
Here we go.
她远离家乡
She was far from home
非常自豪于自己的文化
and proud of her culture,
她在屋里做了很多那种布置
and she set up everything in this room
好让自己觉得舒服
to make herself feel comfortable,
包括她送给我爸的这件和服
right down to giving my father this very kimono
和她画的家乡地图
and laying out a map of her hometown.
路易  听我说
Louis, I want you to listen to me.
他们45分钟后就到了
They are gonna be here in 45 minutes,
如果你还穿成这样
and if you are still dressed like that
这间屋子也还是这个布置
and this room still looks like this,
多米尼克一定会炒了我们
Dominic is going to fire us.
他们不会45分钟后到
They're not gonna be here in 45 minutes,
因为他们已经到了
'cause they're here right now.
田中先生先生
Mr. Tanaka-san.
这是谁布置的
Who did this?
我
I did.
那是四国的地图
That is a map of Shikoku.
是我的家乡
My family is from there.
我知道
I know.
你怎么知道
How?
因为我们做足了功课  先生
Because we do our homework, sir,
正如我们也做足了这笔交易的功课
Just like we did our homework on this deal.
我想我们会相处得非常愉快
I think we are going to get along very nicely.
请坐
Please.
愣着干嘛
What are you doing?
端茶去
Get the tea.
-你让我...  -没错  端茶
- You want-- - Yeah, get the tea.
好吧
Okay.
两位一定就是未来的麦克米伦夫妇了
Oh, you must be the future Mcmillans.
我该说抱歉来晚了  但其实我不是很抱歉
I would say sorry I'm late, but I am not sorry.
我们开始讨论你们
So let us begin discussing the details
第一次婚礼的事宜吧
of your first wedding.
抱歉  请问你是
I'm sorry. You are?
我的名字无关紧要啦
Oh, my name is of no consequence.
重要的是  我们公司已经接手了
What is, is that my company has taken over
纽约广场酒店的婚礼策划事宜
the planning service of the Plaza Hotel.
这是我们的宣传单
Here's our brochure.
从你们脸上的表情可以看出
Mm, I can see by the look on your faces
那个白痴帕特丽夏还没告诉你们吧
that bitch Patricia, she did not tell you.
白痴
Bitch?
我们还挺喜欢帕特丽夏的
We love Patricia.
反正她已经被开除了
Well, she's no longer with us.
如我所说  菜单不能随意选择了
As I was saying, the menu will no longer be optional.
我们只能上鲜橙烩鸭  法式蜗牛
We'll be serving duck a l'orange, escargot,
还有鹅肝酱
and foie gras.
但我们是素食主义者
But we're vegan.
什么意思
What is that?
-就是  -无所谓了
- It's-- - It doesn't matter.
我们是法式餐厅
We are French.
要么吃我们上的菜  要么就别吃
You eat what we serve, or you do not eat.
我们能试吃吗
Can we taste it?
你说在你带我去吃晚饭  和我上床前
Oh, would you like me to just show you my naked body
要不要我先脱掉衣服让你验货
before we go out to dinner and you want to sleep with me?
我要去下洗手间
I need to go to the restroom.
好的  我们这么办吧
Okay, so here's what's gonna happen.
她肯定不想要我了
She's gonna want to drop me,
然后你们就放弃纽约广场酒店吧
and you're gonna drop the plaza hotel.
-什么  -别装了  约翰
- What? - Cut the shit, John.
我这么做都是为了给你个台阶
I did that so you could have some cover.
我调查过了
I did some checking,
你们要么更换举办婚礼的地点
and you either need to change the location of your wedding,
要么我就告诉她你有情妇的事
or I'm gonna tell her about your mistress.
是的
Yeah.
阿加德医生  山姆·塔尔是何时找你就医的
Dr. Agard, when did Sam Tull start seeing you as a patient?
大约六个月前
Approximately six months ago.
他为什么去找你
And why did he start seeing you?
他说他的工作包含着风险
He said his job involved taking risks,
让他压力过大
and it was causing him stress.
所以他是不想继续冒险了吗
So he wanted to stop taking risks?
不  他想要继续
No, he wanted to continue.
我懂了
Oh, I get it.
他想要继续冒风险
He wanted to continue with the risks,
他只是希望心里能好过点
he just wanted to feel better about it.
是的
Yes.
那你有帮助他对于冒险
And were you able to help him feel better
获得心理安慰吗
about taking these risks?
情况是有改善
Um, uh, we made progress.
-请回答是或不是  -是
- Yes or no? - Yes.
那么在你帮助他获得心理安慰后
And after you helped him feel good about taking risks,
他有没有告诉你他一笔交易损失了五千万
did he reveal that he then lost $50 million on one trade?
阿加德医生  你受誓言制约的
Dr. Agard, you are under oath.
如果你不回答
And if you will not answer,
我会请法官强迫你回答
I will have a judge compel you to answer.
有
Yes.
那他关于一笔交易就损失五千万
And how did he say he felt about losing $50 million
是什么心情
on one trade?
他说他觉得愧疚
He said he felt guilty about it.
所以他来找你  好让自己继续冒险
So he came to you to continue taking risks
直到他损失了五千万
until he finally lost $50 million
然后他承认自己有罪
and then admitted to being guilty.
她不是这么说的
That is not what she said.
抱歉  他是有负罪感
I'm sorry, he just felt guilty.
你是想现在就放弃起诉
You want to drop this now,
还是要我把这录音送交证监会
or do you want us to hand this tape over to the SEC?
阿加德医生  刚才的指证是你自愿的吗
Dr. Agard, did you want to give the testimony you just gave?
-当然不是  -为什么
- Of course not. - And why is that?
因为我在乎我的病人
Because I care about my clients.
有没有可能你不愿意
Is it possible that you didn't want to give it
是因为这不是真的
because it's not true?
当然不可能
No, it's not possible.
你不可能会在被迫的情况下
You couldn't possibly have been pressured
做出违背你意愿的证言吗
to give false testimony against your wishes?
不  我不会
No, I couldn't have.
你之前有没有因为受到客户压力
Have you ever been pressured to do something
而做出过违背你意愿的事
you didn't want to do by a client before?
请允许我换个说法
Let me rephrase.
你允许一个你在乎的病人离开了戒毒所
Isn't it true that you released a client that you cared about
就因为受到了
from rehab for no reason
来自另一个雇佣你的客户的压力
other than you felt pressure from a different client
这是不是真的
who was actually paying the bills?
阿加德医生  你受誓言制约
Dr. Agard, you're under oath,
如果你不回答
and if you will not answer,
我会请法官强迫你回答
I will have a judge compel you to answer.
是真的
Yes.
这个人是否在不到24小时的时间里
And did this person die of an overdose
因为吸毒过量死亡了
less than 24 hours later?
是的
Yes.
如果关乎人命的事情
So if you let yourself be pressured
你都能屈从于压力
when someone's life is at risk,
我们怎么能知道
what's to make us think you're not doing
现在就并非这种情况呢
the exact same thing right now?
你这个自大的混蛋
You arrogant piece of shit.
说话小心点  这是我办公室
Watch yourself. This is my office.
我才不在乎
Well, I don't care what it is.
你怎么可以这样背叛我
How dare you betray me like that?
-我提醒过你  -你不是提醒我
- I tried to warn you. - You didn't warn me.
你要我为你说谎  我拒绝了
You asked me to lie for you, and I told you I wouldn't.
我是要你为山姆·塔尔说谎
I asked you to lie for Sam Tull--
这事与山姆·塔尔无关  你也清楚
This isn't about Sam Tull, and you know it.
你说什么呢
What the hell are you talking about?
我向你敞开心扉是为了和你建立信任
I opened up to you so that we could build trust,
不是为了让你羞辱我的
not so that you could humiliate me.
我羞辱你是为了帮助一个
I humiliated you to help a man
你说你很在乎的人
you say you care about.
所以跟我们关于你母亲而吵的架
And our fighting about your mother
一点关系都没有吗
had nothing to do with that?
-你说什么  -你咨询一半的时候走掉
- Excuse me? - You walked out of our session
是因为你不想谈你的母亲
because you didn't want to talk about your mother.
而且一有机会给你破坏
And the second you had the chance
我们的关系  你立刻就抓住了
to permanently damage our relationship, you took it.
你简直疯了
You're insane.
而你是个自私自利的自恋狂
And you're a self-serving narcissist
为了得到自己想要的东西不择手段
who will do or say anything to get what he wants.
我的所做所为只是为了保护我的客户
I did what I did in there to protect my client.
我才不在乎是不是伤害了你的感情
And I don't give a shit if it hurt your feelings or not,
因为你对他的背叛
because you betrayed him
和我对你的背叛没有两样
just as much as I'm betraying you.
你只是因此哭闹
And you may be the one who's crying about it,
但他却要被强加上罪名了
but he's the one who's been accused of committing a crime.
如果你够幸运  有天你会明白
If you're lucky, someday you're gonna realize
现在到底是什么情况  那天到来时
what's really going on here, and when that day comes,
我希望你能找到能帮你的人
I hope you find someone to help you,
因为那人绝不会是我
because it isn't going to be me.
麦克  把咖啡放下来看看这个
Mike, put that coffee down and check this out.
这是斯卡斯代尔的地图  我长大的地方
It's a map of scarsdale-- where I grew up.
田中的回礼
Tanaka returned the favor.
其实  路易  这是我送的
Actually, Louis, I got that for you.
是你  为什么
You did? Why?
因为你是对的  而我错了
Because you were right and I was wrong,
而且虽然听起来疯狂
and as crazy as it seems,
但你我其实合作得还挺好的
you and I actually make a pretty good team.
万事俱备  只差让多米尼克安排见面了
Now all that's left is calling Dominic to set up a meeting.
不如你去吧
Why don't you do it?
我没空
I can't.
我要去把我的地图挂起来
I got to go hang my map.
多米尼克  你在这儿干嘛
Dominic, what are you doing here?
我正想打给你呢
I was just about to call you.
说什么  说你把我的单子搞砸了
To say what, that you blew up my deal?
-我已经知道了  -什么
- Because I already know. - What?
是的  山脉科技在他们听说
That's right. Range Tech called me after they heard
我在跟另一家公司接洽时就联系我了
that I was negotiating with another company.
问题是  我就没在跟另一家公司谈
Problem is, I wasn't negotiating with another company.
谈的是我的律师  还没经过我同意
My lawyers were without my consent.
好的  镇定  多米尼克
Okay, calm down, Dominic.
山脉科技那边有问题
There was a problem with Range Tech.
我说过我不想听到有问题
I told you that I didn't want there to be any problems!
要是你买了他们
Well, if you'd bought them,
他们的问题就变成你的问题了
their problems were gonna become your problems.
你就冷静下来想一想
But just calm down and take a second,
因为我们有解决方案
because we brought you a solution.
什么方案
Which is what?
麦克  别打给多米尼克  田中退出了
Mike, don't call Dominic. Tanaka pulled out.
退出什么
Pulled out of what?
不重要了
It doesn't matter.
你们俩都被开除了
You're both fired.
-哈维  有事找你  -不方便  瑞秋
- Harvey, I need to talk to you. - Not now, Rachel.
-山姆·塔尔被捕了  -什么
- Sam Tull's been arrested. - What?
吉尔罗伊的律师向证监会提交了正式通知
Gilroy's lawyer gave formal notice to the SEC.
不管怎样他们都不用付罚金了
They won't pay the fine under any circumstance.
妈的
God damn it.
格雷琴  打给保罗·吉尔罗伊
Gretchen, get Paul Gilroy on the phone.
哈维  你准备怎么做
Harvey, what are you gonna do?
塔尔不能因为这个坐牢啊
Tull can't go to prison for this.
-没人会坐牢  -你怎么保证
- No one's going to prison. - But how do you know that?
我们之前还没想到他会被捕呢
We didn't think he'd be arrested in the first place.
我不管我们之前是怎么想的
I don't care what we thought.
我不让这件事发生  它就不会发生
It's not gonna happen because I'm not letting it happen.
吉尔罗伊先生接入了一号线
I've got Mr. Gilroy on Line one.
你疯了吗  竟然联系了证监会
Are you out of your mind? You contacted the SEC?
是他们联系的我
They contacted me.
提起恶意诉讼的人可不是我
And I'm not the one who filed a malicious prosecution lawsuit.
不  但你是那个取证的时候死的很惨
No, you're the one who got his ass kicked
然后还敢再回来讨更多打的人
in a deposition then turned around and asked for more.
我没有输得很惨  斯佩克特先生
I didn't get my ass kicked, Mr. Specter.
惨的是那个心理医生  她已经不跟我们合作了
That idiot therapist did, and she no longer works for us.
可你还是没有证据说那些交易
But you still don't have any proof
是我授权的  并且你以后也不会有
that I authorized those trades, and you never will.
所以我建议你别再骚扰我了
So I suggest you stop harassing me
好好去想怎么把你的客户从牢里捞出来吧
and focus on getting your client out of jail.
你听到他说的了
You heard the man.
我们要放弃吗
We're dropping the lawsuit?
不  我们要把损害赔偿翻倍
No, we're doubling the damages.
搞定它
Get it done.
你个混蛋  你设计我们
You son of a bitch. You set us up.
抱歉  路易  我不知道你在说什么
I'm sorry, Louis, I have no idea what you're talking about.
放屁  是你跟田中说别交易的
Oh, bullshit. You told Tanaka not to make a deal.
是我说的
Yes, I did.
这开始听着像个好主意
At first, it looked like a good idea,
但后来我做了尽职调查
but then I did my due diligence,
你瞅瞅  就发现这主意不咋地啊
and lo and behold, it didn't.
在你把会议透给山脉科技前还是之后
Was that before or after you leaked our meeting to Range Tech?
不得不说  我很震惊
I have to say, I'm appalled.
在我和你做了这么多
I mean, after you've been so aboveboard
正大光明的交易之后
in all your dealings with me,
你居然认为我会在你背后捅刀子
to think that I would go behind your back
在没有任何证据指向我的情况下
and leak news of that meeting with no possible chance
说我走漏了会议消息  这想法简直是侮辱
of it being linked back to me, that's really offensive.
它能指向你  逻辑一清二楚
It is linked back to you, plain as day.
那我猜你们俩肯定是证据充足了
Then I guess you two must have some sort of proof,
要是你们没有
because if you don't,
那就请滚出我的办公室
you can walk yourselves the hell out of my office.
跟我斗是一回事
It's one thing for you to have your feud with me,
但你刚刚让你的律所失去了一块肥肉
but you just cost your firm a huge piece of business.
我来跟你解释一下  这话我也跟他讲过
Let me explain to you what I already told him.
这无关生意  而在于一报还一报
This isn't about business. It's about getting even.
哈维  你现在有空吗
Harvey, do you have a minute?
如果你是来劝我放弃反诉的...
If you're here to tell me to drop that countersuit--
我不是来劝你放弃什么的
I'm not telling you to drop anything.
我只是说除了攻击吉尔罗伊
I'm just saying in addition to attacking Gilroy,
我们还应该找证据来证明山姆对那些交易
we should be getting proof that Sam got the authorization
是有授权的
for those trades.
我们没有证据
We don't have any proof.
我们可以  如果能让其他交易员
We can if we get some of the other traders
站出来作证就行
to come forward and say how it went.
他们绝不会作证的
They'll never testify to that.
哈维  那个医师是公司医师
Harvey, that therapist was the company therapist.
那些交易员定期去见她
Those traders saw her on a regular basis
来保证自己精神正常
to keep their shit together.
所以如果山姆跟她谈了工作
So, if Sam opened up to her about work,
其他交易员肯定也说过
then some of the other traders must have too.
她不能说出来
She can't speak to that.
当然可以
Of course she can.
塔尔放弃了医患保密权  其他人肯定也是
If Tull waived privilege, then they all did.
你很清楚
You know that.
那不重要  你也知道我对她做了什么
It doesn't matter. You saw what I did to her.
她不会愿意帮我们的
She's not gonna want to help us.
那不是帮我们  是帮她的患者
It's not about helping us. It's about helping her client.
我不能要求她那么做
I can't ask her to do that.
-为什么  -就是不能
- Why not? - Because I can't.
-哈维  到底怎么回事  -没什么
- Harvey, what's going on? - Nothing's going on.
取证会上她那些事  你怎么知道的
How did you know those things about her in that deposition?
就是知道了
Because I did.
这跟你有恐慌症
Does it have something to do with the fact
而她是你的治疗师这事
that you've been having panic attacks
有关系吗
and that she's your therapist?
-如果有  -我们的对话到此为止
- Because if it does-- - This conversation is over.
我不是想插手什么
Look, I am not trying to butt into things
跟我没关系的事  但这事与你无关
that don't concern me, but this isn't about you.
关系的是不让山姆·塔尔进监狱
This is about keeping Sam Tull out of prison.
你们来这里做什么
What the hell are you doing here?
你俩已经不为我工作了
You two don't work for me anymore.
给我们一分钟解释一下
Just give us a minute to explain.
没什么可解释的
There's nothing to explain.
你们搞砸了我的交易  毁了我的友谊
You blew up my deal and ruined a friendship
就因为你们自以为比我懂的多
because you thought you knew better than me.
我们是比你懂的多
We do know better than you.
你就是个自大的混蛋
You're an arrogant son of a bitch.
多米尼克  这是一份集体诉讼的草稿
Dominic, this is a draft of a class-action lawsuit
被告是山脉科技
headed Range Tech's way
环保局报告一出就会提起
the second the EPA's report comes out.
就是你朋友一直雪藏的那份报告
That's the same report that your friend kept buried.
你要买下他们
And if you'd bought them,
诉讼就是告你了
that suit would have been headed your way.
所以没错  我们是搞砸了你的交易
So, yes, we blew up the deal,
但那人从来不是你的朋友
but that man was never your friend.
你骗了我  而更糟的是
You lied to me, and worse than that,
你不尊重我
you didn't respect me.
对不起  我不该跟你对抗
I am sorry. I shouldn't have antagonized you.
我也不该说不做尽职调查
And I shouldn't have said that rushing through this deal
就快速完成交易是可行的
without doing due diligence was feasible.
重点是  在考虑跟田中交易这事上
You see, the bottom line is, is that we were both right
我们俩都是对的
when we tried to do this deal with Tanaka.
现在我们没什么可对你遮掩的了
And now that we've got nothing to hide from you,
我们会克服一切困难帮你找到别的卖主
there is nothing to stop us from finding you someone else.
那你们与其在这里拍我马屁
So, instead of standing here kissing my ass,
不如赶紧着手去办吧
why don't you get to work doing that?
如果你是来道歉的  那我没兴趣
If you're here to apologize, I'm not interested.
我不是来道歉的
I'm not here to apologize.
我来是因为我需要看你的记录
I'm here because I need to look at your files.
你的自大还真是没有上限
There really is no end to your arrogance.
这是唯一能避免山姆入狱的办法
I wouldn't ask if this wasn't
否则我不会来求你的
the only way to keep Sam out of prison.
我不会给你山姆·塔尔的档案
I'm not giving you Sam Tull's file.
我要的也不是他的
And I'm not asking for it.
我要看你见的其他所有交易员的
I want to see all the files of the other traders you saw.
你是疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
我没有  他们都签了跟山姆那样的弃权书
No, I'm not. They all signed the same waiver Sam did.
肯定有人承认过在巴特勒的工作方式
Some of them must have admitted the way it works at Butler,
那就在你的记录里
and it's in your notes.
我看看我理解的对不对
Let me see if I have my facts straight.
你把我伤个透  还给自己找了理由
You eviscerate me, justify it,
之后又像一切都没发生过一样跑回来
and then waltz back here as if nothing happened.
我没当没事发生  但现在不是时候谈那个
I know something happened, but now is not the time.
不是时候是因为你又需要求我了
You mean now is not the time as long as you need a favor.
该死的  你这不是帮我
Oh, god damn it, you're not doing me a favor.
是帮你的病人  那个你说
You're helping your patient, the one you said
咨询三个律师  就为了不背叛他的那位
you went to see three different lawyers to keep from betraying.
可如果你没有背叛我
And if you hadn't betrayed me,
你现在就不会是这样的境地了
you wouldn't be in this position right now.
你想让我说什么  对不起吗
What do you want me to say-- I'm sorry?
事实上  是的
As a matter of fact, I do.
你以为我想那样贬低你吗
You think I wanted to depose you like that?
我也很痛苦
It made me sick.
我憎恨那过程的每一秒钟
I hated every goddamn second of it,
因为我知道你一直都在努力帮助我
because I know all you've been trying to do is help me,
而我之前没道歉的唯一原因
and the only reason I didn't apologize before
是因为如果知道这就能保证山姆不入狱
is because if I knew it kept Sam out of prison,
我还会再来一次
I'd do it all again.
现在  你愿意帮我了吗
Now, are you gonna help me?
哈维  就算我想帮你
Harvey, even if I wanted to help you,
我的档案里也没那些事
it -- it doesn't say those things in my files.
我还是需要它们
I need them anyway.
我刚说了他们没有你要的东西
I just told you they don't have what you need.
这我知道  你也知道
I know that, and you know that,
但他们不知道
but they don't know that.
你想吓唬他们
You're gonna try and bluff them?
那没用的
It won't work.
你见过我在取证会上对你做的
You saw what I did in there to you,
而且我还不想伤害你呢
and that was something I didn't want to do.
相信我  他们会输的落花流水
Trust me, they won't know what hit 'em.
我们被麦肯诺炒了
We get fired by Mckernon Motors,
你们却没有跟我说  也没跟哈维说
and you didn't tell me and you didn't tell Harvey?
-稍等  杰西卡  -真是够了
- Wait, Jessica-- - God damn it.
我们没说是因为我们是被炒过
We didn't tell anyone because we were fired
不到一天  然后我们又弥补回来了
for less than a day, and then we fixed it.
是吗  弥补回来了
Oh, you fixed it?
是的  那只是个是误会
Yes, it was all a misunderstanding.
多米尼克已经回来了
Now Dominic's back on board.
我才不管多米尼克是不是又回来了
I don't give a shit that Dominic is back on board
弗莱彻引擎公司也不在乎
and neither does Fletcher Engines.
-弗莱彻引擎公司  -没错
- Fletcher Engines? - That's right.
你们被麦肯诺炒掉不到一天
In the less than a day that you were fired by Mckernon,
弗莱彻就成了杰克·索罗夫的客户
Jack Soloff signed Fletcher as a client,
而我如今得放弃麦肯诺了
and now I have to let Mckernon go.
狗娘养的
That son of a bitch.
杰西卡  这一切都是他策划好的
Jessica, he set this whole thing up.
我相信肯定不是因为你跟他作对来着
Oh, and I'm sure you did nothing to antagonize him.
我什么都没干  我发誓  我没有小气
I did do nothing. I swear, I wasn't petty.
我信任他  他却利用这信任
I trusted him, and then he used that trust
在我们背后捅刀子
to stab us in the back.
杰西卡  你真不知道
Jessica, you have no idea.
路易这辈子从没这么睿智过
Louis has never been more right in his life.
你不能放弃麦肯诺  哈维会疯的
You can't dump Mckernon. It'll kill Harvey.
但现在我们也不能代表他们了
Well, we can't goddamn represent them now,
你们也知道
and you know it.
你让杰克放弃弗莱彻  我们就可以
We can if you tell Jack he has to drop Fletcher.
知道你们把我推到什么样的处境上了吗
Do you realize the position you're putting me in?
弗莱彻的价值是麦肯诺的三倍
Fletcher is worth three times what Mckernon is.
很抱歉你的尴尬处境
I'm sorry you're in this position right now,
但这次  害你陷入这种处境的不是我
but for once, I'm not the one who put you in it.
是杰克·索罗夫
Jack Soloff is.
晚餐准备好了
Dinner is served.
我猜你还是给那个臭小子送上结婚大礼了
I guess that means you got opie his bridal gift after all.
没错
I did.
而且我不该在档案室里对你那么不友好
And I shouldn't have been so standoffish with you in the file room.
是我不该让我们的初次会面那么不愉快
Well, maybe I shouldn't have had that be our first interaction.
不  不怪你  怪我
No, that's not on you. That's on me.
我从没欢迎你进入公司  我应该欢迎的
I never welcomed you to the firm, and I should have.
我还是个年轻母亲时
You know, when I was a young mother,
我女儿开学第一周  我每天都送她上学
first week of school, every day I dropped my little girl off.
我一离开她就哭
When I left, she cried.
到周五了我走时  她没有哭
Friday came, I left, she didn't cry.
我却哭了
So I did.
你在说什么
What are you saying?
你没有欢迎我进公司
You didn't welcome me to the firm
是因为你没准备好看你的女儿向前走
because you weren't ready to see your little girl move on.
你是说我把哈维当作我的小女儿啦
Are you saying Harvey is my little girl?
我是说你没准备好向前走
I'm saying you weren't ready to move on.
你很厉害  格蕾琴
You're all right, Gretchen.
希望你喜欢法国菜
Hope you like French.
好啊
Hi.
你没必要专门安排预约
You know, you didn't have to schedule an appointment
来告诉我结果
just to tell me how it turned out.
我是为了来给你这个的
I scheduled an appointment to give you these.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
是山姆·塔尔给的
They're from Sam Tull.
那你给我带了什么东西吗
Did you get me anything?
我有
I did.
我准备好谈我母亲了
I'm ready to talk about my mother.
好漂亮
This is beautiful.
-为什么  -我想庆祝一个特殊的时刻
- Why did-- - I wanted to celebrate a special occasion.
什么特殊时刻
What's the special occasion?
我订到了你生日那天的广场饭店
I got us the Plaza Hotel on your birthday.
举办我们的婚礼吗
For our wedding?
对啊
Yeah.
这是从你向我求婚以后
Oh, that is the sweetest thing you've done
做过最贴心的事了
since you asked me to marry you.
不  这是我做下件最贴心的事前
No, it's the sweetest thing I've done
最贴心的事
until the next thing I do.
迈克
Oh, Mike.
你怎么做到的
I mean, how did you do it?
一定非常难吧
That must have been impossible.
不  小菜一碟
No, it was a piece of cake.
你去找唐娜了吧
You went to donna, didn't you?
所以才是小菜一碟啊
That's why it was a piece of cake.
杰西卡  这么晚了你来干什么
Jessica, what are you doing here so late?
我还没恭喜你签下了
I didn't get a chance to congratulate you
弗莱彻引擎公司
on signing Fletcher Engines.
好事传千里啊
Hey, good news travels fast.
是啊  但你得放弃得更快
Yes, it does, and you're going to drop them even faster.
我猜这跟我们和
I take it this has something to do
麦肯诺马达公司的长期合作关系有关
with our long-standing relationship with Mckernon Motors.
你非常清楚这到底跟什么有关
You know damn well what this has to do with.
我知道我的客户可是国内第四大
I know that my client is the fourth-largest engine manufacturer
引擎生产商
in the country.
如果你光明正大地争取到他们
And if you had landed them like a man,
我会第一个拿着香槟来庆贺
I'd be the first one in here with a bottle of champagne.
但你却是靠坑害同事才争取到的
But you did it by putting a shiv in your fellow attorneys.
所以...结果就是这样
So this-- it's how it's gonna be.
你说的同事  指的是哈维吧
And by "fellow attorneys," don't you really mean "Harvey"?
小心点  杰克
Watch yourself, Jack,
明早前放弃弗莱彻引擎公司
and drop Fletcher Engines by morning.
如果你不放  我也会
If you don't, I will.
明早就放
By morning it is.
到明天下午  整个公司都会知道
And by afternoon, the entire firm's gonna know
你放弃弗莱彻  选了个中等价值的客户
that you chose a mid-size client over Fletcher
就因为哈维·斯派克特喜欢他们
because Harvey Specter has an attachment to them...
而你喜欢哈维
and you have an attachment to him.
我欣赏敢挑战我的人  杰克
I admire people who challenge me, Jack.
但挑战是有极限的  而你正在极限边缘
But there's a limit to that, and you are on the very edge.
我说清楚点吧
So let me be clear.
这是你最后一次跟我合作的机会
This is your last chance to work with me.
抓住机会  你还有前途
Take it, and you have a future.
抓不住  就去丹尼尔·哈德曼那求职吧
Don't, and you can go ask Daniel Hardman for a job,
你我都清楚  抢弗莱彻引擎公司的主意
because we both know that's how you got the idea
跟他们关系大得很
for Fletcher Engines in the first place.